#### PENIEL ENOCH DAVID OPUTA

Toronto/Remote | penielo76@gmail.com | www.penieloputa.com | 825-288-2424 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/peniel-oputa-a23462106

#### **Personal Statement**

Highly skilled and experienced Web Developer and Data analyst with a bachelor's degree in computer science and five years of experience in diverse companies. Strong analytical and problem-solving skills, with the ability to work independently and as part of a team. I am looking to obtain a web developer or data analyst position in a fast-paced organization where I can use my strong organizational and data management skills to contribute to the company's success.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### 1. Extend Communications

(8/2023 - 11/2023)

### Customer Service Representative

Toronto, Canada

• 24/7 telephone answering call center providing customer service, call triage, emergency dispatch, and phone, email, and text coordination for more than 1200 clients.

## 2. CEU (Central European University)

(5/2022 - 12/2022)

Technical assistant

**Budapest, Hungary** 

- Fixing bugs and issues which may occur during classes.
- Daily system checks to ensure 100% functionalities of the systems.
- Ensuring tests and exams are conducted properly with no technical difficulties.
- Ensure all teaching software is properly tested and reviewed before every class.
- Assisting any professors or students who may need any technical assistance.

**3. Exit The Room** (10/2021 - 4/2022)

#### Game Analyst

**Budapest, Hungary** 

- Analysis of online games that are being played.
- Fixed bugs and issues which may occur during games.

## 4. Central Bank of Nigeria

(07/2018 - 10/2018)

#### Intern

Abuja/Nigeria

- Aided the director of the Research department.
- Help assist them in carrying out their day-to-day activities if need be.
- Worked with supervisors to assess the probability and impact of a security breach and developed plans to mitigate such risks.
- Conducted troubleshooting of computer systems as required.
- Acted as a backup for customer service.

#### **SKILLS**

IT Skills: R, Java, Power BI, Python, SQL, Object Oriented Programming, HTML/CSS, Microsoft Office

- Proficient in programming languages such as Java, Python, and SQL
- Experience with web development
- Familiarity with operating systems such as Windows, Linux, and macOS
- Knowledge of database management systems such as MySQL

- Excellent problem-solving and analytical skills
- Strong communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to work independently or as part of a team.

### **Customer Service Skills:**

- Strong communication and interpersonal skills
- Ability to handle customer inquiries and complaints effectively.
- Excellent problem-solving and conflict-resolution skills
- Ability to multitask and prioritize tasks in a fast-paced environment.
- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Experience with customer service and sales

## **Data Entry Skills:**

- Proficient in Microsoft Office Suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint)
- Excellent typing speed and accuracy
- Strong attention to detail
- Ability to work under pressure and meet deadlines.
- Familiarity with database management software
- Experience with data entry and data analysis
- Strong communication and interpersonal skills

#### **PROJECTS**

# Game Using JavaFX

I designed a game similar to the game we all play now called Connect 4. Consider a game board consisting of 6x7 cells, each of which contains a piece of stone and a set of colored (red and blue) stones. The first player plays with the red stones, and the other with the blue stones. The board is initially empty. Players move in turn. In a move, a player must choose an empty cell and put a stone of his or her color into it. The game is over when a row, a column, or a diagonal contains three stones of the same color.

### Software that teaches data structure and algorithm

For my Thesis, I designed Teaching Software. I used Microsoft PowerPoint to create my Teaching Software, which consists of tutorials about Algorithms, Pseudocodes, Searching, and Sorting Techniques. My software focuses mainly on the searching and sorting techniques, how they work, examples, and illustrations to help you understand more about the topic. The software also teaches algorithms. Also, in the end, you have tests, sample questions, and exams to help you practice.

#### **EDUCATION**

**University of Debrecen** 

**Debrecen, Hungary** 

B.Sc. Computer Science

Class of 2020

**Relevant coursework:** Programming languages, Operating systems, Data Structures, and Algorithms, Web application development, Computer security, Applied mathematics.

**Cambrian College** 

Sudbury, Ontario

Postgraduate Degree in Business Analytics

Finished